<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Client on Daniel Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/client/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Client on Daniel Chen</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Daniel Chen {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/tags/client/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a WebDAV Client for Courseworks</title>
      <link>/2013/09/04/setting-up-a-webdav-client-for-courseworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/09/04/setting-up-a-webdav-client-for-courseworks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Columbia University&#39;s Courseworks website allows you to download files for a registered class.  A problem arises when multiple files needed to be downloaded simultaneously.  One simply cannot just select the files and bulk download them.  Courseworks have instructions to circumvent this limitation in the web interface by implementing a 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebDAV&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;WebDAV&lt;/a&gt;
 client.  However, other than Cyberduck under their Mac instructions, the Windows suggestion is quite limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post I discuss setting up a WebDAV Client for Windows and Mac.  If you are on Linux, I&#39;ve only used 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jscape.com/products/file-transfer-clients/anyclient/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AnyClient&lt;/a&gt;
, which is Java based but is not as comprehensive as the Windows/Mac alternatives suggested in this post (and this is the one suggested by Courseworks).  If anyone knows of a good Linux WebDAV client, let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post shows how to setup 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bitkinex.com/download&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BitKinex &lt;/a&gt;
and 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://cyberduck.ch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cyberduck &lt;/a&gt;
in Windows.  You can also use the Cyberduck instructions for Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Courseworks also has instructions on setting up Cyberduck under their Mac section; the same instructions can also be used for the Windows version of Cyberduck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be careful when accessing a directory that you do not own.  There is the potential that you may be able to upload files to the directory, or worse, change, overwrite, or delete the files.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1:  Accessing your Courseworks files and resources links.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you have to do first is log into your Coureworks, click on the course number for your class and then in the left frame of the page click &amp;ldquo;Files &amp;amp; Resources&amp;rdquo;.  On the top of the page you will see a link for &amp;ldquo;upload-download multiple resources&amp;rdquo;, see figure 1.1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will direct you do a link to copy in &amp;ldquo;step 1&amp;rdquo; and directions to set up WebDAV in &amp;ldquo;step 2&amp;rdquo;.  In &amp;ldquo;step 2&amp;rdquo; you will find the instructions for setting up Cyberduck for Mac, which is the same for windows (like I mentioned above).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The link that you need essentially has 2 parts, the part that is highlighted in Figure 1.2 is what you will need when you are using BitKinex, the entire link is needed for Cyberduck,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2a Windows:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Windows I use Bitkinex.  You can also use Cyberduck (which I describe in the Mac section below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download BitKinex 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bitkinex.com/download&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
.  At the time of this post Current Version: **3.2.3 **Release Date: &lt;strong&gt;07/11/2010&lt;/strong&gt;. Do not worry about the &amp;lsquo;older&amp;rsquo; release date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you have BitKinex installed, you will right click &amp;ldquo;Http/WebDAV&amp;rdquo; and go to New &amp;gt; Http/WebDav, See figure 2.1 (sorry my mouse is highlighted over the wrong option).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;][5]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A popup window will appear for a name, you can simply put &amp;ldquo;Columbia&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;newcourseworks.columbia.edu&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;courseworks.columbia.edu&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, it should direct you to a settings menu under the &amp;ldquo;Server&amp;rdquo; option on the left, See Figure 2.2.  for server address enter &amp;ldquo;courseworks.columbia.edu&amp;rdquo;, I used &amp;ldquo;newcourseworks.columbia.edu&amp;rdquo;, but I believe the two should be the same, and the former may be preferred.  You can also refer to Step 1 and copy the text I showed that was not highlighted in blue (Figure 1.2).  Under Authentication, enter your UNI for &amp;ldquo;User&amp;rdquo; and password for &amp;ldquo;Password&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;][6]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2b Mac:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyberduck can be found 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://cyberduck.ch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
.  I am using the Windows version of Cyberduck, the Mac should look almost the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Courseworks have the following instructions on their site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the &lt;strong&gt;Open Connection&lt;/strong&gt; button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the &lt;em&gt;Server&lt;/em&gt; dialog box, type (or copy and paste) the path as shown above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type in your Sakai username and password and click &lt;strong&gt;OK&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will now see a window on your Mac screen that represents the resources that are in your site. Simply drag and drop between this window and other Finder windows on your Mac to transfer files to and from your Sakai site&#39;s resources folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be showing a different method, all have the same results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the bottom left of the application, click on the &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; sign (Figure 3.1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[5]: {{ site.baseurl }}/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/webdav03.png
[6]: {{ site.baseurl }}/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/webdav04.png&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
